Matthew Jerich

MatthewJerich@gmail.com ❖ (707) 592-8938 ❖ San Tan Valley, AZ ❖ github.com/MJerich ❖ linkedin.com/in/mjerich

SUMMARY

I am a full stack web developer with a well rounded skill set, being proficient in both the front and back end. I am currently on course to graduate from the Michigan State University coding bootcamp in July 2022. I am experienced in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Node.js. I have built several full stack projects both on my own and as part of a team. I am very excited to continue learning and sharpening my skills to build and maintain exciting products.

SKILLS

- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python
- Applications and Tools: Visual Studio Code, Git, Github, GitLab, Heroku, React.js, Bootstrap, jQuery, jQuery UI, Node.js, Express.js, Express-sessions, mySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Object-Oriented Programming, RESTful API, ORM, MVC, Jest, bcrypt, Handlebars, Insomnia, Postman, Linux

PROJECTS

Discord Bot

- Made a bot with various features using the Discord API and Discord Python libraries.
- Project code: https://github.com/MJerich/ZeldaBot

E-Commerce Back End

- Developed the back end for an e-commerce website. I used Express.js API and Sequelize to manage and interact with a MySQL database.
- Project code: https://github.com/MJerich/reign-mart-e-commerce

Tech Blog

- Built a full stack blog site similar to a Wordpress site, where developers can publish their blog posts and comment on other developers posts as well.
- Project code: https://github.com/MJerich/reign-tech-blog
- Live Application: https://reign-tech-blog.herokuapp.com/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Target Mar. 2015 – Present

Inbound Expert

Oueen Creek, AZ

- Maintaining and up-to-date inventory of merchandise and supplies by scanning barcodes or manually entering information into a computer system.
- Monitoring inventory levels to ensure that items are restocked when needed.
- Ensuring that merchandise is properly displayed and priced according to company standards.
- Maintaining a safe work environment by following all safety policies and procedures.

Sport Chalet Oct. 2007 – Oct. 2014

Sales Associate/Master Bike Mechanic

Vacaville, CA

- Managed a high-volume workload within a deadline-driven environment.
- Identified customer needs and provided recommendations to give customer solutions, informed supervisors and leads accordingly.
- Acquired Master Mechanic Bicycle Training.
- Used Integrated Store Operations (ISO) to receive, organize, and shelve products.

EDUCATION

Michigan State University

Jan. 2022 – Expected Jul. 2022

Full Stack Coding Bootcamp

• A 6 month course that covered front and back end web development.

Will C. Wood High School

2004 - 2008

3.5 average GPA

INTERESTS

• Interests: coffee, brazilian jiu jitsu, 3d printing, music, yoga, video games, esports, thrifting